Finding aid to Ruth Lee Kennedy papers CA.MA.00157 ======= Finding aid to Ruth Lee Kennedy papers CA.MS.00157 >>>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22
Smith College Archives
Ruth Lee Kennedy papers
1900-1989
1930-1988
Smith College Archives
Kennedy, Ruth Lee, 1895-
CA.MA.00157
CA.MS.00157
1.667 linear feet (3 containers)
The papers of Ruth Lee Kennedy contain material related to her career at Smith College and the University of Arizona as professor of Spanish literature and her distinguished career as a scholar of Spanish literature's Golden Age (17th century), especially the works of Tirso de Molina.
Biographical / Historical
Ruth Lee Kennedy, a professor at Smith College, was regarded as the world's foremost scholar on the 17th century Spanish dramatist Tirso de Molinathe. She was also the first American woman to lecture at Oxford and Cambridge universities in England. Born on October 15, 1895 in Centerville, Texas, she was the daughter of Oliver William Kennedy and Carrie Lee McWaters Kennedy. Professor Kennedy did her undergraduate and masters level education at the University of Texas in Austin (B.A., 1916; M.A., 1917) in Spanish language and literature. She did further graduate work at the University of California, Berkeley (1924-1925) before completing her Ph.D. at the University of Pennsylvania in 1931.
Professor Kennedy began her teaching career as a teacher of Spanish in the San Benito, Texas (1917-1918) and Temple, Texas (1918-1919) high schools. She served as an instructor in the Oklahoma College for Women (1918-1919), at Sam Houston State Teacher's College (1920-1921), at the University of Puerto Rico (1921-1922), at Southwest Texas State Teacher's College (1922-1926) and at San Antonio Junior College (1926-1930). Professor Kennedy was appointed to the Spanish Department at Smith College in 1930 and taught there until her retirement in 1961. She was made full professor in 1944, served as chair of the department and as head of the Smith Junior Year in Spain (1956-1958.). During those years she also taught at various colleges and universities in the United States and lectured both here in the United States and in Spain, England and Germany. She received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1951 that allowed her to further her studies in Spanish literature, as well as fellowships from the American Association of University Women and the Jusserant traveling fellowship of the University of Pennsylvania.
After her retirement from Smith College in 1961, Professor Kennedy moved to Tucson, Arizona and assumed a professorship at the University of Arizona from which she retired in 1970. In 1979 Professor Kennedy was admitted to the Academia Norteamericana de la Lengua Espanola, the American branch of the Real Academia Espanola. Among her other honors was the Festschrift published in 1977, Studies in Honor of Ruth Lee Kennedy edited by Vern G. Williamsen and A. F. Michael Atlee (Chapel Hill, N.C. and Madrid). In retirement, Professor Kennedy continued to do research and publish.
In her lifetime Professor Kennedy was regarded as the world's foremost scholar of the 17th century Spanish dramatist Tirso de Molina, who was the topic of one of her books, Studies in Tirso (1974), and of numerous articles. In addition to her book study of Tirso, Professor Kennedy also published the book The Dramatic Art of Moreto (1932); she published nearly 50 articles in her long career. She was a mentor to numerous younger scholars, a fact evident in the collected correspondence of these papers.
In retirement in Tucson, Professor Kennedy enjoyed gardening and was often cited for her gardens in Tucson publications. She died on February 4, 1988 at age 92 in Tucson. Her ashes were buried in the family plots in Houston, Texas.
The Ruth Lee Kennedy Fellowship at the University of Arizona and at Rice University is given to students of the Golden Age literature. At the University of Texas at Austin Professor Kennedy established two fellowships in honor of her parents: the Carrie Lee Kennedy Fellowship (for graduate students or undergraduate students of exceptionally outstanding ability who are studying Golden Age of Spanish Literature) and the Oliver William Kennedy Fellowship (for a graduate student or a faculty member for travel to Spain or other European countries to do research in the Golden Age of Spanish Literature). The Ruth Lee Kennedy/Fulbright travel grant is co-sponsored by the International Institute in Spain and the Commission of Cultural, Educative and Scientific Interchange between Spain and the United States is granted to Spanish women, lawyers or doctors who wish to carry out investigation projects or extended studies in a university in the United States.
Scope and Contents
The Ruth Lee Kennedy papers contain biographical materials, some items from her youth and early years as a teacher of Spanish literature and language and portraits and photographs of Kennedy and her family. There are extensive files of correspondence received by Professor Kennedy related to her professional activities among Spanish literature scholars in the United States and Europe as well as from other academicians. There are a few letters of Professor Kennedy's. Correspondents include, but are not limited to: Maria Araujo-Fernandez, Jamie Asensio, J. B. Avalle-Arce, Hannah E. Bergman, Alice H. Bushee, John Brooks, Courtney Bruerton, James A. Castaneda, Jill Ker Conway, J. P. Wickersham Crawford, William J. Entwistle, William L. Fichter, Robert A. Folchi, Otis H. Green, Guillermo Guastavino, John Hull, Lloyd Kasten, L. Klaiber, Irving A. Leonard, George E. McSpadden, G. Marañón, Thomas C. Mendenhall, Sylvanus Griswold Morley, Joaquina Navarro, Emilio Navarro Sanz, Tomas Navarro Tomas, Jack H. Parker, Manuel Penedo Rey, Agapito Rey, Miguel Romera Navarro, Nina Scott, Lesley B. Simpson, Gerald Wade, Bruce W. Wardropper, Margaret Wilson and Maria Eugenia Zornoga de Marques. The correspondence is arranged by date.
The papers also include lecture and research notes. Professor Kennedy's notes are usually written in pencil in very small handwritten letters on small pieces of paper and assembled in small bundles-the back of an envelope, half sheets of letter sized paper or other small sheets. Often the content of a given group of papers is unclear; an anonymous individual has very helpfully identified many of the bundles of papers with precise notes as to the content of a particular bundle.
The papers are arranged in the following series:
I. General Biographical
II. Photographs
III. Correspondence
IV. Publications
Related Material
University of Arizona Libraries
42. Biographical file. Kennedy, Ruth Lee
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently. Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently. Minutes of the Faculty Council are closed to all except current Smith College Faculty for a period of 75 years following their creation. Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Ruth Lee Kennedy papers were created and/or assembled by Professor Kennedy, Professor of Spanish Literature at Smith College (1931-1961) and at the University of Arizona (1961-1970) and were donated by her to the College Archives.
Smith College -- Faculty
- Series I: General
  - Biographical materials (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">1)
  - Curriculum vita, lists of RLK's publications, etc. (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">2)
  - Guggenheim application, 1951 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">3)
  - Transcripts and certificates, 1920s (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">4)
  - Addresses, etc. (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">5)
  - University of Pennsylvania items, 1930s-1970s (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">6)
  - Smith College appointment papers, 1931-1959 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">6a)
  - University of Arizona appointment papers, 1961-1968 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">7)
  - General miscellaneous, 1930s-1980s (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">8)
  - Valedictory address (high school), by RLK, 1912 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">9)
  - Poetry, by Steve, 1920s (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">10)
  - The Alamo (yearbook) - San Antonio Junior College, 1928 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">11)
  - Writings, by E. C. Kennedy (RLK's brother), 1970-1980s (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">12)
  - Marta Antonio Estades Saez - Certificates, 1940-1952 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">13)
  - Passports and international certificates of vaccinations, 1936-1966 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">14)
  - European library cards, etc., 1937-1958 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">15)
  - Award certificates, identifications, etc., 1940s-1980s (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">16)
  - Grade book - San Benito High School, Texas, 1917-1918 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">17)
- Series II: Photographs
  - Photographs of RLK, Late 1900s-early 1910s (?) (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">1)
  - Portrait of RLK, 1918 or 1919 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">2)
  - Portrait of RLK, 1925 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">3)
  - Portrait of RLK, 1932 or 1933 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">4)
  - Portrait of RLK, 1936 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">5)
  - Portrait of RLK, 1951 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">6)
  - Portraits of RLK, undated (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">7)
  - Photographs of Carrie Lee McWaters Kennedy and RLK (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">8)
  - Photographs of RLK (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">9)
  - Portrait of Ernest C. Kennedy and of RLK and her family (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">10)
  - RLK at Smith College (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">11)
  - San Jacinto Museum (Texas) (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">12)
  - Photographs of friends (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">13)
  - Photographs - Smith College in Spain (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">14)
  - Photographs - Europe (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">15)
  - Portraits - Unidentified individuals (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">16)
  - Christmas greetings received (photographs) from various individuals (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">17)
  - Photographs of RLK in formal dress (Kennedy Photo Service, Houston, Texas)
- Series III: Correspondence
  - Correspondence to and from RLK's mother, undated (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">1)
  - Kennedy Chronicle - RLK's Christmas letters, 1955-1988 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">2)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1937 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">3)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">4)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">5)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">6)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">7)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">8)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">9)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">10)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">11)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">12)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">13)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">14)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">15)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">16)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">17)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">18)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">19)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">20)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">21)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">22)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">23)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">24)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">25)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">26)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">27)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">28)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">29)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">30)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">31)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">32)
  - Correspondence - On Tirso manuscript, 1972 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">33)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">34-35)
  - Retirement, University of Arizona - Program, speeches, letters of appreciation received, 1970 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">36)
  - Retirement, University of Arizona - Guest signature book, 1970 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">37)
- Series IV: Publications
  - Attacks on Lope and His Theatre in 1617-1621 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">1)
  - Certain Phases of the Sumptuary Decrees of 1623 and their Relation to Tirso's Theatre, 1942 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">2)
  - The Close Friendship of Gabriel Tellez and Perez de Montalvan: its Possible Significance for the "Segunda parte of Tirso -- and Addenda, 1972-1975; (1975-1976) (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">3)
  - "El condenado por desconfiado": 1st Ambient and its Date of Composition, 1974 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">4)
  - "El condenado por desconfiado": Various Reasons for Questioning its Authenticity in Tirso's Theatre, 1976 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">5)
  - "El condenado por desconfiado": Yet Further Reasons for Questioning its Authenticity in Tirso's Theatre, 1976 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">6)
  - Concerning Seven Manuscripts Linked with Moreto's Name, 1935 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">7)
  - Contemporary Satire Against Ruiz de Alarcon as Lover, 1945 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">8)
  - The Date, Significance and Organic Unity of Mira's Dyptich on Ruy de Avalos and Don Alvaro de Luna (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">9)
  - The Date of El "Amor medico" and "Escarmientos para el cuerdo": Tirso's supposed trip to Portugal in 1619 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">10)
  - Did Tirso Send to Press a Primera parte of Madrid (1626) which Contained El condenado por desconfiado (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">11)
  - Escarraman and Glimpses of the Spanish Court in 1637-38, 1941 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">12)
  - "La estrella de Sevilla", Reinterpreted (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">13)
  - Estudios sobre Tirso, 1, 1983 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">14)
  - La gala del nadar-date and authorship (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">15)
  - Has Tirso Satirized the Conde-Duque de Olivares in Nineucio of Tanto es lo de mas como lo de menos?, 1980 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">16)
  - Literary and Political Satire in Tirso's "La fingida Arcadia", 1964 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">17)
  - The Madrid of 1617-25: Certain Aspects of Social, Moral, and Educational Reform (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">18)
  - Las mangas cortas in Lope's Theatre (1611-1616): Their Importance as a Tentative Norm for Chronology, 1962 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">19)
  - Moretiana: A Source for El caballero, 1939 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">20)
  - El mundo literario de Madrid, en una comedia de Tirso, 1979-1980 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">21)
  - Notes on Two Interrelated Plays of Tirso: El amor y el amistad and Ventura te de Dios, hijo, 1960 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">22)
  - On the Draft of Five Plays by Tirso de Molina, 1942 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">23)
  - Pantaleon de Ribera, "Sirene," Castillo y Solorzano, and the Academia de Madrid in Early 1625 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">24)
  - La perspectiva politica de Tirso en "Privar contra su gusto", de 1621, y la de sus comedias politicas posteriors, 1981 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">25)
  - Philip IV's Advocacy of San Blas on February 3, 1623: Its Reflection in the Blas-Menga "Romancero" and the Works of Gabriel Tellez, 1976-1977; (1978) (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">26)
  - "La prudencia en la jujer" y el ambiente quella produjo, 1949 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">27)
  - A Reappraisal of Tirso's Relations to Lope and his Theatre, 1965-1966 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">28)
  - La renegada de Valladolid, 1937 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">29)
  - Sin honra no hay valentina, 1939-1940 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">30)
  - Sobre la relacion de Tirso con Cervantes, 1979 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">31)
  - The Sources of La fuerza del natural, 1936 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">32)
  - Studies for the Chronology of Tirso's Theatre, 1943 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">33)
  - The Theme of "Stratonice" in the Drama of the Spanish Peninsula, 1940 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">34)
  - Tirso's Desde Toledo a Madrid: its Date and Place of Composition, 1971 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">35)
  - Tirso's "El mayor desengano": Its Date of Composition, Its Ambient, and Its Interpretation, 1976 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">36)
  - Tirso's No hay peor sordo: Its Date and Place of Composition (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">37)
  - Tirso's "La republica al reves" Its Debt to Mira's "La rueda de la fortuna": Its Date of Composition, and Its Importance, 1973 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">38)
  - Tirso's "La venturea con el nombre": Its Source and Date of Composition, 1969 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">39)
  - Tirso's La vida y muerte de Herodes: Its Date, Its Importance, and Its Debt to Mira's Theatre (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">40)
  - Tirso's Satire of Ruiz de Alarcon, 1964 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">41)
  - Varia: Moreto's Span of Dramatic Activity (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">42)
  - RLK's book reviews on other writers (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">43)
  - Book reviews on RLK's publications (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">44)
- Series V: Lecture and Research Notes, including related teaching activities
  - Smith College Junior Year in Spain and other Spanish language and literature activities at Smith College, 1950s-1960 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">1)
  - University of Arizona Ph.D. requirements in Spanish, 1960s (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">2)
  - Grade books - University of Arizona, 1961-1970 (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">3)
  - Course introduction (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">4)
  - Introductory notes, course assignments, test questions (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">5)
  - Introductory materials on Spanish literature - Research notes, lectures and bibliographies (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">6)
  - Spanish literature through the 15th century - Lecture notes and course outline (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">7)
  - Smith College - Spanish language and literature - Miscellaneous (Box 3, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">8)